<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4001/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4001/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-10T11:14:54+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4001/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Stan Bright</title><subtitle>Founder of SaaSHub &amp; LibHunt. Having more ideas than time. Ruby on Rails enthusiast. 🥑👉🍞 p.s. Sweat dreams are made of hard work. Who am I to disagree?</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The 3 Day Domain Name Rule</title><link href="http://localhost:4001/3-day-rule/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The 3 Day Domain Name Rule" /><published>2020-09-10T10:30:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-09-10T10:30:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4001/3-day-rule</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4001/3-day-rule/">I will share one of my little &quot;secrets&quot; that have saved me hundreds
or thousands of dollars - &quot;The 3 Day Domain Name Rule&quot;.

__The Rule__
&gt; Whenever you have an idea of a great domain name,
&gt; wait for 3 days, at least, before buying it.

It's that simple. However, be warned, there might be an uneasy feeling
that someone is going to grab the domain before you. It will be haunting you
on the back of your mind. You have to resist it and stick to the rule.
Both your future self and your money will thank you.

Also, you could be thinking &quot;*But, it's only $8.95*&quot;. Yet, **it's more**. Usually, a few times more.
Let me tell you why. We, people, hate losing things that we own.
Hence, once you own the domain and have put your credit card in, it is very very likely
you will be paying for that name for a few years. Domain registrars
are aware of that, too. That's why the registration price, on many platforms, is
%30 - %50 less compared to the following up renewals.

Here it is an example with GoDaddy: Reg $12; Renewal: $18 (+50%).

{% include post_img.html src=&quot;3-day-rule/godaddy-dotcom-price-2020.png&quot; %}

I'd say that you will keep your shiny new domain, on average, for 3 years at least.&lt;br/&gt;
That makes ~$50!, and NOT $11.99.

**.io** domains are the worst. First, they are heaps more expensive - $54 to reg it
and $60 to renew =&gt; a $174 [idea ownership cost](/idea-ownership-cost). What is more,
they seem short, trendy, and many of them are not registered yet. If you are building
a tech product, you will be lured into buying one of those. Do yourself a favour and
either try coming up with a **.com** name or at least apply the rule and don't rush.

Now, back to the rule. At some point, after buying many domains and losing some money,
I realised that my enthusiasm for the &quot;great&quot; idea I had the day before would
start disappering more often than not. Only the &quot;good&quot; ideas stuck for longer than a few days.
Then, I came with this rule of thumb for myself - never buy a domain name without waiting for
at least 3 days after coming up with the idea of it. I've never had a single case when
someone else would grab the domain before me. NEVER. The closest one was about 3 months afer I had the idea.
The domain name was _vivanotes.com_ if you are curious. To be honest, it felt a bit bad,
as I still had the idea written down in my notes. Yet, I will most probably never build
that project and have saved hundreds or thousands of dollars along the way.

**Why 3 days**? There is no scientific reason! It's easy to remember, it's longer than a weekend
and it works for me.</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Ideas" /><summary type="html">I will share one of my little “secrets” that have saved me hundreds or thousands of dollars - “The 3 Day Domain Name Rule”.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“Why” questions and why to avoid them</title><link href="http://localhost:4001/why-questions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“Why” questions and why to avoid them" /><published>2020-09-09T07:11:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-09-09T07:11:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4001/why-questions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4001/why-questions/">_Don’t ask questions that start with “Why” unless you want your counterpart to defend a goal that serves you. **“Why” is always an accusation**, in any language._

The advice of avoiding &quot;why questions&quot; is from the book [&quot;Never Split The Difference&quot;](https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/26156469-never-split-the-difference)
by Chris Voss. If we think about it, how straight to the point is that?
When was the last time someone asked you
&quot;Why this&quot; or &quot;Why that&quot; and you weren't left with a bit of sour feeling.
For example, many bosses would use &quot;why questions&quot; in meetings after something
had gone wrong (_&quot;Why did you do that&quot;, &quot;Why didn't we sell enough&quot;, &quot;Why couldn't we release on time&quot;, etc._).
However, that might be counterproductive in many cases.

The better alternative is asking calibrated and open-ended questions that direct
the other person towards solving your problem. Such could be &quot;How&quot; or &quot;What&quot; -
_&quot;How can we solve this problem?&quot;_, _&quot;What can we do to improve the process?&quot;_, etc.
Coming up with these non-why questions will lead to better results for both parties
in most cases. Moreover, they may start flowing naturally to you once you remember
to avoid &quot;why questions&quot; in negotiations as a rule of thumb.</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Wisdom" /><category term="Books" /><category term="Never Split The Difference" /><category term="Negotiations" /><category term="Advice" /><summary type="html">Don’t ask questions that start with “Why” unless you want your counterpart to defend a goal that serves you. “Why” is always an accusation, in any language.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello world</title><link href="http://localhost:4001/hello-world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello world" /><published>2020-09-08T09:00:50+10:00</published><updated>2020-09-08T09:00:50+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4001/hello-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4001/hello-world/">I have decided to start blogging again. I used to blog relatively regularly about 10 years ago.
More or less, when I was actively developing svejo.net. Then I stopped.
Blogging requires consistency, time, dedication and even more.
However, you reap the benefits much later. I guess that’s the reason why many people stop blogging
(apart from moving to walled gardens like Medium, Twitter, LinkedIn, FB, etc.).

Yet, I’ve been observing a slight renaissance in blogging in the last year or two.
That and the idea that one improves his thinking by writing, made me wanna start blogging again.

I have also had the idea of building an RSS reader.
It has been boiling at the back of my head for almost a year.
I even bought a domain a few months ago. I have the mantra that one should use
what he is building if he wants to make something useful.
I think that taking an active part in the blogging community would be the best
way to experience the genuine needs of an RSS reader user.

So, let’s see what happens.</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Meta" /><summary type="html">I have decided to start blogging again. I used to blog relatively regularly about 10 years ago. More or less, when I was actively developing svejo.net. Then I stopped. Blogging requires consistency, time, dedication and even more. However, you reap the benefits much later. I guess that’s the reason why many people stop blogging (apart from moving to walled gardens like Medium, Twitter, LinkedIn, FB, etc.).</summary></entry></feed>